Awesome, now that we understand the key value structure of JSON and are able
非常好 现在我们已经了解了 JSON 的关键值结构
to identify individual JSON components, we can use this knowledge to help us
可以识别各个 JSON 成分了 我们可以利用这一知识
navigate through the JSON response to extract fields we're interested in.
在 JSON 响应内容中进行导航 从而提取出感兴趣的字段
In other words, we'll use this knowledge to find a path from the root
也就是说 我们将利用这一知识点 找到一条路径
of the JSON response all the way down to the value we're interested in,
从 JSON 响应内容的根开始 遍历途中各个节点
traversing nodes along the way.
直到找到我们感兴趣的值
Let's revisit this Twitter response from the last quiz.
让我们再次访问上一测验中的 这部分 Twitter 响应
Let's say we wanted to extract the hashtags associated with Chris'
例如 我们想要提取有关 Chris 最近第四条
fourth most recently favorited tweet,
最受欢迎推文的话题标签
which is about a basketball shot made from a stadium hallway.
内容是从体育馆走廊里 投球
I've gone ahead and formatted the response to be more human-readable
我已经提前对响应内容进行了 格式处理 即放到
by throwing it into jsonformatter.curiousconcept.com.
jsonformatter.curiousconcept.com 中 让它的可读性更高
With everything expanded,
全部内容展开后
we notice that at the root we have a JSON array as indicated by this bracket.
可以发现 在根这里 从这对儿中括号可以看出 这是一个 JSON 数组
Then if I collapse all the nodes, I can see that
如果折叠所有节点 可以看出
this array contains JSONObjects with data that we can interpret.
这个数组中包含 JSONObject 我们可以 解释其中的对象数据
This array most likely holds the most recent tweets
数组中很可能含有 以时间倒序表示的
in reverse chronological order.
最近发布的推文
If we expand one of these entries, we can confirm that there is a JSONObject
展开其中一条 我们就能够确定 其中包含的 JSONObject
that holds data representing a single tweet.
存储着表示一条推文 的数据
In order to get the fourth most recent tweet,
为了获取最近 第四条推文
we'd have to access the fourth element of the array using index three.
需要使用第三条索引来访问数组的 第四个元素
So if we count through the indices, we have index zero, one, two, and three.
所以我们来数一数索引 索引零、第一、 第二、第三条索引
At this index, we have the single JSONObject which we can navigate
在这条索引中有一个 JSONObject 我们可以通过 entities 键
deeper into by getting the JSONObject referenced by the entities key.
引用的 JSONObject 进一步深入导航
Then we can extract the value of the hashtags key which is a JSON
然后 可以提取 hashtags 键对应的值 其中存储着全部
array holding all the hashtags.
话题标签的 JSON 数组
Once we're here, we need to start processing each entry one at a time.
从这里开始 需要一次 一个地处理每条内容
For each JSONObject in the array we'll need to extract the text string
对于数组中的每个 JSONObject 我们都需要提取出
referenced by the text key.
text 键引用的文本字符串
In this case, the first hashtag being nba, the next being knicks.
在这个例子中 第一个话题标签是 NBA 第二个是 knicks
In summary, we had to traverse a sequence of the JSON components to get
总而言之 要获取感兴趣的值 我们需要遍历一系列
the values we were interested in.
JSON 成分
Let's take another look at the path.
我们再来看看路径
Starting at the root, JSON array, three, zero,
从根开始、第三个 JSON 数组 零
one, two, three, returns a JSONObject,
一、二、三 返回一个 JSONObject
then we use the entities key to get another JSONObject.
然后利用 entities 键 获取另一个 JSONObject
Then we use the hashtags key to get a JSON array that contains
然后利用 hashtags 键获取包含 话题标签 JSONObject 的
the hashtags as JSONObjects.
JSON 数组
Finally, for each JSONObject,
最后 针对每个 JSONObject
we use the text key to extract the individual name from each hashtag.
利用 text 键提取 各个话题标签的名称
So what's the point of all this?
那么这样做的目的是什么呢？
What we just did was to isolate a path through the JSON components
我们所做的是从响应内容的 JSON 成分中
of this response in order to get to the data we care to extract for our app.
划分出一条路径 从而获取要 为应用提取的数据
The same logic that we used to traverse this response is the same path
我们用来遍历响应的逻辑 正是代码
traversal that our code should follow in programming the steps to parsing or
在编写 JSON 响应的解析或解构步骤时 应该遵从的
deconstructing the JSON response.
相同路径遍历
In this next quiz, you'll practice traversing a JSONObject
在下面的测验中 将练习 遍历 JSONObject 树
tree to find the nodes you're interested in.
从中找出感兴趣的 节点
To expose you to the other examples of JSON responses,
为向你展示其他 JSON 响应示例
we'll look at a sample response from the Instagram API.
我们将阅读一条来自 Instagram API 的 响应示例
Instagram is a popular photo and video sharing social media app.
Instagram 是一款极受欢迎的分享照片、视频 的社交媒体应用
They expose an API where you can programmatically access information
利用其提供的公开 API 可以 以编程的方式访问
about the media files.
有关媒体文件的信息
This URL gives us access to information about a specific media file.
利用这条 URL 我们可以访问有关 某特定媒体文件的信息
Click on the RESPONSE button to see a sample response.
单击响应 (RESPONSE) 按钮 查看响应示例
Chris posted this image to his Instagram account.
Chris 在他的 Instagram 账户上 发布了这张图片
And we made a request for this specific image to the Instagram API and
在向 Instagram API 发送关于 此特定图片的请求后
received this JSON response back.
我们收到了返回的 JSON 响应
This includes information about the image, such as tags, filters,
其中包含有关图片的信息 例如 标签、滤镜
the time it was taken, and a link.
拍摄时间和一条链接
In this quiz, you'll take a closer look at this response and
在此测验中 将更深入地 了解响应
answer some questions.
并回答一些问题
So what I want you to do for this quiz,
在此测验中 希望你能够
is to determine the traversal path to certain fields of interest.
确定对于某些感兴趣字段的 遍历路径
For example, find the traversal path of which nodes you must cross in order to
例如 找出遍历路径 遍历在查看图片所获 点赞数量时
find the number of likes for an image.
所必须经过的节点
Let's do the first one together.
我们先来一起完成第一个内容
So if I scan this real quick, it looks like there's a count key
那么 快速浏览后我们发现 在 likes 键当中
inside of a likes key, that's probably the number I'm looking for.
存在 count 键 这很可能就是我要找的值
To find the traversal path we need to specify how to get from the very root,
要找出遍历路径 需要指定 如何从根开始
top of the JSONObject, all the way down to the likes key value pair.
也就是 JSONObject 的顶部 直到获取 likes 键值对
In fact, the count key value pair inside of the likes.
实际上 是 count 键值对 而不是 likes
First, we start at the root,
首先 从根开始
then we traverse to the JSONObject with the key data.
然后遍历具有 data 键的 JSONObject
There are a bunch of attributes within here but
其中有很多属性 但是
the one we're interested in is the key likes.
我们感兴趣的只有 likes 键
We know that the key likes maps to a JSONObject because of the curly braces.
从大括号可以看出 likes 键 映射一个 JSONObject
Within there, we want the count key, which maps to an integer of 5.
其中 我们需要的是 count 键 count 对应整数 5
So going back to our quiz, we type this out to express the path we need to
那么 回到测验中 我们可以键入 获取 count 键值对
follow in order to get the count key value pair.
所需遵从 的路径
Repeat a similar process for the rest of these fields of interest.
对剩余的其他感兴趣字段 重复相似过程
Write out how you can traverse from the root JSONObject all the way to
写出如何从根 JSONObject 一直遍历到
the appropriate key value pair.
正确的键值对
You can use the dash symbol and
至于箭头符号
right angle bracket to type in an arrow symbol.
可以使用短线和 右尖角号输入
When you're done, click Continue.
本课到此结束 请单击继续 (Continue)